[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
I'm coming.
I'll have more brought out at once.
Everything is in order.
-Bun-hong.
-Yes, madam?
Where is Mistress Yun?
Uh. W-Well, she's…
Gentlemen,
your presence here does me honor.
Why, you're nearly grown up, Won.
Thank you, Uncle.
How has your health been?
Fine. Though, I wish I had some of yours.
Won, I've prepared a new weasel-hair brush
of black bamboo to present to the elder.
Would you be so kind
as to fetch it from the study?
-Well, boy?
-Yes, I'll go at once.
Sir, this is not a place
a man may enter freely.
I could say the same.
A woman has no right
to behave this way in my uncle's study.
Oh, it's you. Won.
Cousin Yun?
You've grown into a fine young man.
I almost didn't recognize you.
Oh, no! The new brush!
Uncle asked me to fetch it for him!
You've already stained the weasel-hair!
Surely, someone would have
used it before long.
I don't see the trouble.
And he was laughing so heartily.
I was taken aback.
-Oh, look, he's brought it back.
-Ah, that's the brush?
What's this, Won? Did you use the brush?
How could you have shown such disrespect?
Won, explain yourself to the elder.
-Well, you see, I--
-Now, wait just a minute.
Why don't we first have a look
at what young Master Won has written?
You did write this, didn't you?
Tell us the truth now.
I would like to see it as well.
My goodness. Brother, look at this.
Here, read for yourself.
Well now, what a clever lad he is.
Will you please Explain the merits
Of the sacred herb from the south
Tobacco?
The examination hall
Becomes quite a spectacle
Whose son could he be?
His scholarship is truly exceptional
Thankfully, I have made
A good living with this pansori
Ha! What else to say?
So I'll sing it for you
As you want me to
Wishing you'll get to the top
My lord, if I may.
Even if you slip the examiner
A few coins…
-It isn't much, but still.
-Oh, you shouldn't have.
Or look around for clues
A stiff neck
And bad headache you'll get
Even with a good cheat sheet
-Take a seat.
-Oh, what's the use?
This one copies secretly
All the answers
And this one
Doesn't even bother hiding it
-That is not true!
-You even copied his name.
And what about that scholar
With no advantage and no luck?
-No, it's not what you think.
-You've disgraced yourself.
There is nothing under heaven
that escapes my notice.
He is expelled
From the examination hall!
-Faced with an unprecedented question
-Not another word!
The hall falls into confusion
Such as the graceful crane
With calm, serene eyes
A faint smile upon his lips
Beautiful brushstrokes appear
Like a black dragon
Soaring to the sky, so strong
It can reach the blue heavens
Behold!
He is here
Yes, he is right here!
The royal flower gets you at the top
It's him
He is right here!
My worries for you were mountainous,
knowing you had only that taciturn
father of yours to study under.
Tell us, Won,
surely you must have
at least one literary companion?
Someone with whom you exchange letters
and share a friendship through words?
We'll clear the table now, my lord.
He's such a clever lad,
I'm sure he has many such friends.
And if he doesn't,
there's no one to blame, save his father.
As his father, I humbly apologize.
His cleverness shone through
the recent initial examination as well.
Who would have known His Majesty would ask
about the virtues of tobacco?
Yes, indeed.
Won, why don't you share with us
what you wrote?
Recite to us your answer.
As tobacco's bitter scent
fills my mouth with smoke,
the words I wished to say
can no longer come out,
and regret fills my heart.
But before I can give my emotional speech,
I breathe out smoke instead of words.
Thus, none may hear me,
which is the rightful path
of a loyal subject.
It is indeed.
A flawless answer, young man.
I have no doubt he will achieve top honors
in the palace examination.
I'm honored, but whatever I achieve
is thanks to my literary friend.
Shut up, you fool! Why would you attribute
your cleverness to somebody else?
Besides,
if this literary friend was so great,
his name would've been well known
long ago.
You make a good point.
Have you ever given me the opportunity
to make my name known?
The elder speaks true.
One thing's for certain,
when the boy talks,
he most certainly takes after his father.
It seems our clan's future
rests on you alone.
All thanks to you, dear cousin.
Because of you, I have deeply felt,
and come to know many things.
Miss Yun, where are you?
The madam is looking for you!
Please, Won.
You already had plenty of talent.
I merely showed you the way.
Did I not tell you to stay
by Yun's side at all times?
I'm sorry, madam.
But you know how Miss Yun can disappear.
Not only are they honored
to be deemed worthy of your clan's seed,
but when they heard
the bride would be taught to read and draw
by such a virtuous lady,
even the mother
was ready to be considered.
As I told you before, the elder daughter
is gentle and comely like her father.
The younger takes after her mother
and only really shows a head for trade.
Therefore,
you only need to look at the elder.
Silk! Silk for sale!
-Look! It walks on its hands.
-Oh, my!
The finest silk from China.
The highest quality at a lower price.
Come, have a look.
We are honored
to have you call on us, madam.
Goodness,
I never thought I'd meet you in person.
Are these all the pallets
of tobacco you're selling?
No, certainly not.
We keep the stock
worthy of guests elsewhere.
These shipments
were too damp to sell here,
so we set them aside.
We'll send these to Hwaseong instead.
Hwaseong?
His Majesty is carrying out
some great project in that district.
Workers from all across the land
have gathered there.
And what do workers do when they gather,
but smoke tobacco merrily?
Oh, how can I put it better?
Kill two birds with one stone.
Kill a bird with stones.
Madam, allow me to escort you inside here.
Yes, madam.
Do follow us to the inner quarters.
I knew it.
Since you recognize it,
I'm glad I spent all that money.
I can scarcely contain my joy.
A genuine Saimdang
grass-and-insect painting.
Is it not truly beautiful?
Uh, madam.
As you enjoy these things,
I have something else
that may be of interest.
If you like,
I will take you to it at once.
My word.
You have an original Master Danwon?
Yes, we certainly do.
You have no idea how many people told me
how knowledgeable you are
in matters of the arts,
but for a novice such as I,
your keen insight is truly overwhelming.
Is she not breathtaking in person?
No?
-Huh.
-Your thoughts, sir?
Hmm.
My lady, bearing a child
with this girl will be difficult.
-You have done well.
-Yes, my lady.
What on earth are you talking about?
What a lovely house you have,
it's decorated with exceeding taste.
Yes.
You have not simply displayed
your precious items,
but used them to create harmonious
splendor which delights the eye.
I find it most enjoyable.
Yes. Well…
A humble novice such as myself cannot rest
until she gets her hands
on something of value.
Would you like one of them?
Please, take any painting
you wish as a gift.
I can even summon Master Danwon himself.
Would that it were a suitable match,
but alas, it seems it was not meant to be.
I brought the refreshments
you asked for, Mother!
Uh, we made fresh juak.
Please enjoy them, madam.
Oh… uh…
What's wrong? They're really tasty.
What?
Damn you, you quack.
Hmm.
Mmm.
They're really good.
Hmm.
I will move here.
That's my final decision.
What do you think of that?
Hmm?
Let's see.
Mm-hmm.
He made the most wonderful move just now.
I guess he fell asleep
before my turn was over.
Mark my words, he will rise higher
than anyone in our house.
He's been staying with us for six days.
Shouldn't your great-nephew
return to his home now?
What harm is there if he stays, hmm?
That way, when he's gone,
we won't miss him as much.
You truly rate his worth that high?
Is he not extraordinary?
Just last year, he would throw the stones
all over the chamber.
But now, he has become a worthy opponent.
All right.
Your arms.
Simply lovely, truly.
When you go, this is what you must do.
Stand someplace
where the lord will notice.
Then say to him, "I have brought
a gift for your lady wife."
Then you give him a look like this, "Ooh."
Show me you can do it.
Go on. That's it. Like…
Like this?
That's it! Exactly!
Hmm?
Uh, hello, my dear. And you are?
Good day, my lord.
Oh.
My lady. I found this, um…
My mother bid me to come here with this.
She said it must be delivered
to you today,
so I came here as soon as I could.
The way you're soaked in the rain,
it's quite bold, my dear.
Your mother personally bid you
to come to me in the rain,
with no jangot to cover yourself?
Come inside and get warm.
You will return when the sun has risen.
You tell your mother
that I hold her wisdom in high regard,
but there are lines she mustn't cross.
Gye-hwa, bring something for her
to change into and some hot water.
Yes, madam.
What a vulgar family.
To waste a young girl's health
on a meager gift.
If the day passes smoothly,
there's no cause for concern.
It troubles me
to see a young girl stricken.
Especially one who came as a guest.
Prepare some medicine as well.
At once, my lord.
Has she eaten anything today?
Yes, my lord. We prepared a porridge
for the girl, as madam instructed.
You feed mere porridge to a sickly girl?
-Here, take this a moment.
-Yes, my lord.
Oh, dear.
My humble thanks to His Lordship.
Pick only those that are without blemish.
Mind the pathway.
See there?
That patch of ground has sunk again.
-I see it now.
-Spray some water on it at once.
Madam, it is I, Gye-hwa.
Permission to enter?
And what could that be?
It's from the Lady of the First Rank
in the Left State Councilor's household.
It is a velvet antler.
Hmm.
It would appear by this,
the lady has something to say to me.
Find something fitting to send in return.
If she wishes to see me, I shall oblige.
It's been too long since you last called.
To tell the truth,
I've been terribly lonesome here.
My sincerest apologies.
I should not have delayed.
I hope all is well in your household.
In mine, yes.
It would seem that your house
is where the disorder lies.
Really, my dear,
it seems to me that
a man's heart beats in your womanly chest.
You would personally
select Lord Yoo's concubine?
Ah.
You know as well as I,
that Bukchon's walls
are built lower than most.
Tell me, when shall you bring her in?
I am still looking for her.
One cannot bring just any girl in.
There are many things to consider.
Hmm.
Recently, your husband sent mine a gift.
It was a considerable amount of tobacco
of the highest quality.
But I thought the Lord Councilor
had left such ways behind.
Oh, my.
Has this news really passed you by?
Whatever could you mean?
The concubine,
has she not already been selected?
Where else could this high-quality tobacco
have come from then?
Haryanggyo is the only answer.
It seems that Lord Yoo,
has already developed quite a taste
for the merchandise of that little shop.
Was that not what you were planning?
Is that not why you took that girl
as his concubine?
-Make way, make way!
-Get those boxes and move them.
My word, what is all that commotion?
Oh, my goodness. Look at that.
If you didn't know better,
one might think they were wedding gifts
for a family with an upcoming marriage.
I suppose I'd be grateful
for a nobleman's seed too.
-Put the crops on that side.
-All these marvelous objects.
-Inside that box?
-Sell my daughter for less.
Hush! What if madam hears you?
The lady's coming out.
Pallets over to the left side,
parcels to the right.
-Hey, be careful.
-Put your back into it!
Push, man!
Oh, madam, right this way.
Boxes this way!
Be careful with that.
Whoa, this item is precious!
Madam. Madam, madam.
I'm certain I told you
not to come anywhere near us.
What is the meaning of this?
Please excuse me, madam.
I received your message,
but ignorant wench that I am,
I felt I had no choice but to do this.
-That's why I came to see you.
-I have no reason to accept these,
so take them back at once.
Madam!
-Gye-hwa, come.
-Yes, ma'am.
Turn this lady out of doors.
-Madam!
-This way.
I see you're displeased.
I understand that at least.
How could it be otherwise?
We are both but women.
What?
Madam, a lowborn wench like I,
shall never forget what you have done
by showing favor to my girl.
I am sure that without your leave,
His Lordship
would never have come to visit me,
and tell me he'd chosen my So-ok himself.
One thing,
is there a date you'd like to take her in?
I will make sure to teach her properly
by then and send her to you straight away.
I am ever so grateful, madam.
Hmm, let's see. Then we go like this.
Let me try now.
-Like this.
-Oh, please, my lord, stop moving!
All right. All right,
all right, all right. Try it like this.
Oh.
-Please make it again.
-Yes, of course.
Now, do try your best this time, hmm?
Here.
Let's see.
The mistress of the tobacco shop
was here earlier.
It seems that vulgar woman
came by unannounced.
You must have been quite surprised, dear.
That girl.
Do you find her to your liking?
My lady,
I told you many times it was unnecessary,
but you would not be dissuaded.
I'm truly sorry for making you
bear this burden alone.
It's not a position of great importance.
I thought someone like her would do well.
Madam, a gift has arrived from
the Chief Royal Secretary's residence.
And ladies from other various houses
have also sent some small gift boxes.
Shall I bring them in together?
Oh, that is too much.
I was visiting
with my sixth cousin's maternal aunt.
She's close with the tobacco shop woman,
and she told me that the second daughter
has already gone
to visit the lord in the night.
Let's just say, she wasn't so innocent.
-Oh my, that indecent girl!
-Good heavens.
Some say they've even heard
the sound of a baby crying
from the Master of Rites' quarters.
With child before me?
No girl is that fast.
According to what I heard,
it's the girl's mother who the lord
has been having indecent relations with.
Is that so?
Surely not.
The Minister would not
involve himself with that wench.
Whatever the case may be,
they say the girl was with child already.
To avoid a scandal, Lady Cho is making
a pretense of taking in a concubine,
to appear generous.
To think of how loftily she held herself.
Come to think of it, it's been some time
since we sent her gifts.
Yet she still hasn't--
Madam.
I could hear your peals of laughter
all the way from my inner chambers.
It seems you were sharing an amusing tale.
Please do share it with me as well.
I am most curious.
It had been so long since I heard
from you, I wondered if you would come.
Mmm. The fragrance is quite lovely here.
Yes, indeed, as is the weather.
Aren't I pretty?
I'm getting better. Look.
One, two…
Look, Mal-ttong!
You should try.
Oh!
I noticed that spring
had arrived in full this morning.
I wanted to bring some of it to you.
I hope you slept soundly last night,
uh, madam.
Cho-hui.
What flower is that?
It's lovely.
What lovely petals.
Do you like them as well?
Perhaps they aren't
so beautiful after all,
for yours is the lovelier spring.
How do you do that, madam?
Sound so smart when you talk?
Your eyes fill with tears
surprisingly quickly.
Well, your heart is young still.
You brought the flower,
you may leave me now.
Yes.
Thank you so much for your time, my lady.
Mun-heul.
This is the pen name I gave myself.
I hope, like the moon
that rises highest in the night sky,
that my writings
will at least flourish in darkness.
Even if in my lifetime,
they never see the light of day.
That is why it is such comfort to me
that I can share myself with you.
From now on, I will write to you
with my pen name.
Speaking of which,
if you are so inclined,
would you use the pen name, Cho-hui?
It's Nanseolheon's real name.
On my way back from the village school,
a flower petal fell,
and landed softly in my hand.
It felt as though fate itself had decreed
it should come directly to me.
I held it in my hand and brought it home.
I'm entrusting my fate to you.
Please do not lose it.
My lord.
You have a letter!
Oh my…
I'll leave it here.
-How does it taste?
-Mmm.
I heard the Chief State Councilor's wife
has a pipe no less than nine cheok long.
That is what their steward said.
The pipe is so long
that her maidservant had to go
to the next room to light it.
"Dearest? Have you put it in yet?"
"Of course! You must suck harder, madam!"
-That's very good.
-Oh, my lord.
MUN-HEUL
Excellent.
-Is that so?
-Yes.
-Mine tastes somewhat sour.
-Oh?
There's a note of tartness in the throat.
-Ah, the throat, huh?
-Mmm.
Oh. No, it needs more.
Does that tartness
give you a sense of pleasure
as you inhale it?
-My! That sounds like my first time.
-Or does it…
I want to smoke that.
I would give anything
to feel that way again.
Oh, it's from Samdeungcho.
I knew the men from there were a bit tart.
Be quiet.
-Get out now.
-What was that?
Cho-hui!
MUN-HEUL
What's changed, young master?
You never used to eat
things like this before.
To my cousin, Cho Won.
Spring has already begun
to gently ripple through Bukchon,
and it would appear
through my heart as well,
for I find, I miss you more than ever.
Have you been well all these years?
I must see you, dear cousin.
So please, come to see me with all haste.
I have been enduring all this time
and can no longer bear the longing.
Be careful not to step on the flowers.
Bring some more!
Madam, Lord Cho Won is
on his way to Hanyang.
Look at everyone.
It's the entire kingdom.
-I've got 15 on that guy!
-Oh, yes, lift him up
-Throw him down, like that!
-He's down! He's down!
Hey, hey, so you're telling me
You're going to bet some money? Huh?
The palanquins all line up
-Snip, snip, scissors are cutting yeot
-Sticky sweet yeot for sale!
It is so sweet, it is to die for
-You could die eating it
-Come on, who wants some yeot?
-And you might never know
-I want some.
-Please, Mom? I want some.
-Hanyang's white yeot
Where are you going in such a hurry?
-Spreading in the air
-Why don't you and I have a drink?
-The scent of plum blossom
-You know where to find us.
Which fellow is it today?
Huh? Which one?
Look at this man, look at that man
They're coming here
Swarming after profit
Then they go their separate ways
It's Hanyang, the walled city
Cross Gwangtong Bridge to the south
Then you arrive in Namchon
Where you'll find
Most of the common people live
If you cross to the north
You arrive in Bukchon and its nobility
Bukchon is such a sight
It's just wonderful!
Make way, move aside! Please, move aside!
Move! Stand aside!
Out of the way at once!
Make way at once!
Palanquin bearers
Of high-ranking officials
Wild animals even hide away
And birds do fold their wings
Within the walls of Hanyang Fortress
It's unrivaled
Don't you think? Huh?
Whether it is true or not
Bukchon
I will escort you
to the inner chamber, my lord.
Madam, Lord Cho Won has arrived.
You may enter.
It seems the journey to Hanyang
has been quite a lengthy one for you.
I needed time to decide
whether I should even come to this place.
This is my first visit,
and I did not know the way.
Have you been waiting long?
Have you been well, my lady?
The moon waxes and wanes.
The flowers bloom in abundance
with every change of season.
So have I been…
very well indeed.
You're very beautiful
as always.
In truth, I have something
I wish to ask of you,
my dearest cousin.
A wish, you say?
What is this wish
that made you write to me
after such a long silence?
We have decided to take a concubine.
Which brings me to the thing
I would ask of you.
The girl's name is So-ok.
I want you to put a child
in her belly, yourself.
What?
If I refuse…
will today be the last time I see you?
You know I will always be by your side.
But you said yourself
that this was a place
where you had better not come.
Is that so?
I've heard that you pass your time
by picking all the beautiful flowers
outside of Hanyang.
So why don't you show me
the man you've become, dear cousin?
Show me your famed expertise.
You want me to bed a young girl
I could woo with a glance?
Sounds like a waste of my talent.
At that age, a strong wind
is enough to sweep them away.
Which is why it should be simple enough
for you to accomplish.
Why haven't you sired
a child of your own then?
Wait. Is it my brother-in-law?
Certainly not.
How could there be any fault
with my husband?
Rather, it is due to my lack of virtue.
I was taught propriety.
A lady always knows to hold her tongue,
and do her best
to support her husband in silence.
Is that right?
But still,
why must I father this child?
Because it's always been my wish…
to hold a child in my arms
that has your eyes.
That would be the pleasure
of my remaining years,
to hold that child and know the truth.
My dearest cousin…
are you saying…
that you still hold me in your heart?
Then…
you feel the same?